I start off by going to deepseat.com.
Put /en if you want to go straight to
English. Top right there is a API
platform link. Hit that. It'll ask you
to sign up or log in. I like logging in
with an existing Google account. It's
the easiest way. Once you're logged in
though, on the left, hit API keys.
This is going to be your identity when
you use the API. Hit create new API key.
Give it a name. Any name works. And then
hit create API key. Now, it's going to
show you the API key one time. You can
always create a new key. It takes 10
seconds here, but copy this and either
keep the key somewhere safe or if you're
going to use it right away, I just drop
it into Notepad temporarily, but copy
that key cuz it's about to go away and
you're not going to see it again. Click
done. And then in the left nav column,
hit top up. This is where you add money
to your account so that you can call the
API. The minimum amount is $2. If you're
wondering how far is $2 gonna get you,
that will take DSVK's Crime and
Punishment, one of his shorter novels,
from Russian, translate it to English in
conversational English, then give you
morphological analysis of every single
word. So all the grammatical details of
each word
in JSON format, plus that dynamic
English translation, all for $2.
So, it's a very cheap API. Start with
just the $2, but put in your credit or
debit card details. Hit pay down at the
bottom. And once payment is successful,
hit done. It's all you need to do on the
DeepSeek platform itself. Now, let's use
this. I keep all my coding projects in
an apps folder in the C drive. I'm going
to open that up. Create a new project
folder. I'm going to call it DeepSync
API. Then inside of that, I'll create a
Python file. You can do a new text file.
Name it whatever you want. PY. Hit
enter. I'm going to open this up in my
VS Code. And then I just have an example
script in the description of this video
that you can paste in here, but any
Python you have will need some sort of
variable for the API key. So I paste my
API key into that variable string and
save the whole file. To run this, open
up your command line interface. I like
PowerShell. On Windows, you can always
search for cmd and open command prompt.
To navigate up to my C drive, I type cd
backslash. Navigate into my apps folder
with cd space apps and then into my
project folder with cd deepseeek- ai.
hitting enter. And then to call the
DeepSeek API from code, I'm going to
need some sort of a client library.
DeepSseek uses the same API structure as
OpenAI, which is not surprising because
they stole their models. It's a lot
easier for me just to use the OpenAI
client Python library. I can install
that with pip space install space
OpenAI.
Hit enter. Give this just a couple
minutes to install on your computer.
Once that's done, I can run my Python
file
command is python space and then my file
name including the extension py. And
that python code in the description just
allows you to send questions to
deepseeek through your command line
interface here. So I can type out a
question, hit enter, and then my Python
code will call the deepseeek API.
Deepseek API answers are not easy to
process. They got a lot of information.
It's messy. But somewhere in this
response, there's the answer I'm looking
for. If I ask a follow-up question,
DeepS has no idea what I'm talking
about. Every call has no context beyond
the call. So you have to put in any
information relevant to what you're
doing in the prompt that your Python or
other code sends.